Hey guys, welcome back. So in this
session we are going to set up Tska
server and uh we are going to see what
all services are available. So on this
picture we see how the TSA architecture
is uh distributed and uh we are talking
about the TSA server. Now within TSCA
server you can see there are lots of
different services. Um some of them like
the rest API service, the file service,
the dex monitor, uh dex server,
automation object service and uh license
administration and also authentication
service. Right? So all of these services
uh they work from the TSCA server and
they are connected to different
components as you can see um across the
TSka architecture right. So there is the
database tire um then there is tasks CI
client which helps uh in building CI/CD
pipelines and then there are the agents
uh DEX agents right which are also
connected to uh the DEX server uh in TSA
server and then there's the license tire
and then there's the TSA commander at
the end right so all of these are
connected to each other and uh you have
to set up TSA server uh if you want to
manage all of these different components
within the toka architecture. Okay. So
we are going to see um how we can uh set
up toka server and then later on we'll
also see how you can set up dex agents
and um how you can then trigger test
events from the toka commander which
will then reach to the dex server and
then um they will be triggered in these
dex agents.
Okay. So, um to set up Tska server, it's
not that difficult. Okay.
So, it is pretty similar to how we uh
set up TSCA commander. Okay. So, we have
got a .exe and I have downloaded it
already on my machine. Uh where you can
get this again. Uh go to the Tricentis
support portal and go to product
support. uh go to the relevant TSCA
version which you want to download. So
go to the download section. Here you
will find all the different versions but
I have picked uh the latest version TSCA
16. Okay. And uh this is the TSA server.
You can see here just click on this uh
and it will download that particular
version. So I have updated my TSA
commander from 14.3 to 16.0 zero for
this particular uh session and that is
because um they don't have uh that old
um TUSCa server version which is
available for download here. So
uh and I thought it's better uh to
update the TSCA version to the latest
version. So finally I have done that and
I've also uh downloaded the TSA 16.0
server now. Okay. So uh we are going to
install this now and as I said uh it's
not pretty complicated um you just need
to follow uh the software installation
process right so click on continue it
will uh install all these prerequisites
if they are not
present and then um it will install all
these different services which we saw in
the diagram you can see gateway license
administration DDS is uh AOS distributed
execution file service REST API. Okay.
So all of these services should be
available on your
machine. Um I will choose the default
location. You can always change it. Uh
you can select or deselect this
option. And here uh something important.
So we have two options to set up Tska
server either through HTTP or
HTTPS. For HTTPS uh you will require a
certificate thumbrint. Okay. And it
should match. So that's what uh is
required for HTTPS. So I generally
prefer HTTP for this setup. And uh by
default port 80 should be um should be
available if you're installing this on a
server. Uh so but for me it's not
available. So I will use 8080. Okay. So
which matches the local host uh of my
server or this
machine. And then I'm going to click
next. This is the install location for
file service.
And these are all the services. Okay.
And it will start uh installing
now. So one thing uh to note is I'm
doing all this setup on my local. So
both TSCA commander and server would be
running in my local. Uh it's not a
recommended setup for a production like
environment. It is just for uh demo and
practice. Uh we are looking at this but
uh you can get a different Windows
server, right? uh and make sure it is it
is of uh higher configuration because
Tska server does take up uh little more
resources than uh Tska commander because
so many services are running okay so
it's better to have a TSCA server uh a
dedicated uh server for TSA server okay
which could be a windows uh windows
server and uh this could be a physical
server or a cloud server uh it's up to
too. But uh it should be a dedicated
server uh mostly. Okay. And uh when you
work in real projects, you will have
these servers which are dedicated for a
TSCA server and then you will have
different machines for TSK commanders
and then different machines for TOS TSA
DEX agents. Right? So these are the
three main components uh which you need
to set up uh in your infrastructure and
uh that way uh it will be better to
manage and also it will be efficient and
faster. Okay. But for practice purpose,
you can always go ahead and uh set up
TSA server on your machine if your
resources are good and it can handle um
this load of both TSA server and
commander uh running at the same time.
Okay. So this will take some time uh to
install um all the services. So let's
wait until this is finished.
If you want to follow along then uh go
ahead and download the TSA server 16.0
or any other version. Uh it should match
uh whatever TSA commander version you
have uh on your machine currently. So
either upgrade it to 16 and then uh
install 16 or um download the server
version which is available on the
support portal and which matches the
commander version. Okay. Uh so that is
important.
So as you can see the installation was
completed uh without any problem. It is
going to open the TSA server in your
browser and also the settings page.
Okay. Uh we will look into both of these
pages and what it means. Okay. So uh
while managing the TSCA server um either
as an admin okay or as an user uh who
has got this access to this server you
need to look at all these different
services okay. So this is the Tska
dashboard you can say and uh it contains
some of the uh services which are
important for Tska server also when you
click on this settings. Okay. So, it
opens this settings page and uh here you
can see all the different ports and
configurations for each service. Okay.
Which if you want to change you can
change it
here. And as soon as you change
something uh you click on save then this
service is going to be restarted. So if
something is not available or not
running here right. So all the services
should be in running state if you are
currently using it. If something is not
running you can come here and click on
save. It is going to restart the
services. Okay. And after that uh it
should be in the running
state. Um you're not going to use all of
the services but whatever services you
are using so uh do take care of the
ports where they are running right. So
these are all the endpoint URLs like for
text this is the endpoint URL
currently.
Um and similarly every service has got a
particular port. Okay. And that port
should be available on that particular
machine or server otherwise your service
would be affected. Okay. Now the other
way uh to restart your services is you
can also go to your task manager.
Okay. And there uh you will go to
services and go to tricentis and you
will find all the different services
here. And I can either stop or start
this particular service. Okay. like this
one. I can start this service although I
may not be using it. Okay. I can also go
ahead and restart any particular
service. So when you restart it goes to
stop and then starts running. Okay. Um
and similarly you can also go and search
for services. Okay. Here it's the same
thing but
um from Windows you can find your which
service you want to restart and all the
services are listed here uh and their
status. So you can monitor your services
right from here and restart if they are
not in running state.
Okay. So there are three ways you can uh
maintain your uh TSA server
services. And coming
back to
our our TSA dashboard, uh you can see
all the major services here like the TDS
test data services. This is the license
administration. This is the user
administration and this is the
administration console. Okay. Um and one
of the important ones we are going to
look at is distributed execution. Okay.
Uh which is also known as text. We are
going to talk about this. Um and when
you click on this it actually takes you
to the monitor. Okay. And in the monitor
uh this is a web page where you can
monitor your uh all your test events
which are triggered through DEX okay on
different agents. So if you have set up
any particular agent, it will be uh
available in the agent view. Here you
can see all the agents which are set up
and connected to the TSA machine. Okay.
Or TSCA different
commanders. Um so all the agents which
you set up they will be available here.
You can see their state whether they are
running or they are in some error state.
So you can monitor everything here. You
can also restart all the agents from
here. Right? So currently I don't have
any agents running. So it is showing uh
zero agents. Um also in the event
whatever test events we are going to
trigger uh whether they are passing,
they are in running state or they are
failing right. So everything will be you
can monitor it right here or you can
also uh stop those test events if you
don't want them to run right from here.
Okay. So this is called uh the event
monitor. It is part of the TSCA server.
So once you set up Tska server, this
event monitor URL would be available for
you.
Okay. Right. Um so this was all about
the TSA server. Um obviously there are
lots of different configurations which
you need to do if you want to work. Uh
we'll see one of them. uh for
distributed execution we need to change
some configurations um and all of it
would be uh done on C program files. So
you can go to that location where your
TSA server is currently present. Go to
tricentis tuska server and here you will
find all the folders for all the
different services and inside this you
will find different configuration files
um which you might need to tweak in
order to um get it running uh for you.
Okay. So here we have also got the dex
monitor and dex server you can see.
Okay. So we are going to see um how you
can change some configurations here uh
in while we talk about the distributed
execution.
Okay. So this was all about uh TSA
server. How you can set it up, how you
can maintain your TSA server and all the
different services which are running
with TSCA server and also uh you can
view the DEX monitor right from a URL um
or from your dashboard. Okay. So this is
the TSA
dashboard. Yeah. And next we are going
to talk about the distribution services
or uh the distribution execution. So
which is known as text.